<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>OpenDC Ltd - UK</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on OpenDC Ltd - UK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of Open Datasets</title>
      <link>/services/service_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/service_01/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC can help you find among the thousands of webpages the open data sets that can help your organisation unlock new insights. Some of this data will be too big to be analysed by usual tools like Excel. OpenDC can help you load and analyse this data using open source programming tools such as Python libraries or PostgreSQL databases. Once this data is identified and loaded, OpenDC can help you analyse the patterns in the data, cross the information with external independent datasets to find correlations, answer the questions you have asked and perhaps the ones you have not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mapping and other visualisation</title>
      <link>/services/service_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/service_02/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC mainly uses the QGIS framework as a Geographic Information System (GIS) tool. With QGIS, OpenDC can provide communicative maps as well as perform advanced GIS analysis such as the analysis of catchment areas but also advanced routing features. OpenDC can also provide GIS training in general and on QGIS in particular. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can help you use GIS features if you are working for a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>QGIS Plugin Development</title>
      <link>/services/service_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/service_03/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC can develop for you custom QGIS plugins under the QGIS API. Note that any QGIS plugin that is publicly released has to be open-source. You can however use your plugin internally if you do not want to release the code. 
How this service can help your organisation You might be interested in a custom QGIS plugin if you are working for a
Non Governmental Organisation (NGO) with interesting geographical datasets that you want to make available to the GIS community in order to enable the wide analysis of this data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Process automation</title>
      <link>/services/service_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/service_04/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC mainly uses open-source tools and languages but stays pragmatic when a language or an application is popular but not open-source. Therefore OpenDC also uses the VBA language to automate processes on any Microsoft Office application. Python, C++ and SQL are generally used for any other applications. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can help you automate your processes if you are working for a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Assistance on mobility studies</title>
      <link>/services/service_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/service_05/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC&amp;rsquo;s founder has over 10 years experience in transport and pedestrian modelling projects, working in London, Paris and Guinea Conakry. OpenDC can help strengthen your team on high profile mobility projects with advanced modelling and project management skills. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can help you in your mobility project if you are working for a
Local council and want to be advised on a mobility study you would like to launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile phone and GPS data analysis</title>
      <link>/services/service_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/service_06/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC&amp;rsquo;s founder has developed an expertise in the use of mobile phone data (GSM) and GPS data to understand people movement. This expertise involves the data collection, storage, cleansing, filtering processes using different mathematical tools, scaling, bias correction, aggregation, analysis and visualisation. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can assist you with GPS and mobile network data if you are working for a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Commuters carbon emissions</title>
      <link>/work/work_79/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_79/</guid>
      <description>Client:   Partners: -  Sector: Web development   The context: 
The world global warming and current energy crisis are pushing us, people, companies and public bodies to limit our carbon emissions. To do so, we first need to understand their sources before being able to reduce them. In France, 30% of the carbon emissions come from the transport industry. The transport in France has many purposes, the commute being a significant one in terms of volume.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GPS data processing</title>
      <link>/work/work_80/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_80/</guid>
      <description>Client:   Partners:   Sector: Mobile data analysis   The context: 
GPS data is available to any business willing to purchase it through data brokers. This data is collated from hundreds of mobile applications with different attendance types: news, online shopping, socials medias, games, sports etc. Our partner and us were curious to fully understand this data strengths and limitations in the context of mobility studies.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedestrian Modelling Software</title>
      <link>/work/work_91/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_91/</guid>
      <description>Company: Movement Strategies Ltd     Client: Internal project   --  Sector: Pedestrian modelling   There should have been a video here but your browser does not seemto support it.Example of simulation of the egress of the Beyoncé and Jay-Z concert at the Nice Allianz Riviera Stadium in 2018. 
What we did:  We developed a pedestrian dynamic assignment software, with an assignment algorithm based on fluid mechanics principles.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobility diagnosis in Seine-et-Marne</title>
      <link>/work/work_83/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_83/</guid>
      <description>Client:   Partners:   Sector: Data analysis   The context: 
The Seine-et-Marne department (77) is the largest department in the Paris region, occupying almost half the area of the full region. It is made of a mix of rural areas as well as dense areas or under heavy development (Marne la Vallée sectors including Disneyland, etc.). The local authority stakeholders wanted to get a global vision of the mobility patterns in this inhomogeneous territory as well as an understanding of its public transportation gaps, without having to run a long and expensive survey.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile phone data analysis</title>
      <link>/work/work_86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_86/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners: CDVIA  --    Sector: Mobile data analysis   The context:  The Région Sud, a French public administration in charge (not only) of the public transportation service, wants to investigate the use of mobile network data (MND) to understand the transportation needs and behaviours across the South-East region of France. They launched a public tender in May 2019 on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Data collection web app</title>
      <link>/work/work_85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_85/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Webapp link: my-places.app   Sector: Web development   The context:  The need for centralised on-site data collection is found in every sector. Tools such as Google Maps or Mapstr can help but they do not provide a dedicate database for your organisation and team. This tool is a free web app, mobile friendly and password protected that enable you to store and comment all your favourite places, without sharing them widely on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Rail Data lake</title>
      <link>/work/work_87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_87/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners: CDVIA  --    Sector: GIS processing and data analysis   The context:  Our client (Network Rail) manages the rail infrastructure in the UK. Theirs assets (rail, overhead structures etc.) properties are stored in a central database. Modern measurement systems embedded in high speed trains enable to measure some properties of these assets, like the height and stagger of an overhead electrification line at a given location for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimode accessibility</title>
      <link>/work/work_88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_88/</guid>
      <description>Client: Confidential   --  --  Partner: CDVIA  --   Sector: Mobility studies   The context:  Our client (a French public administration) has 1000 employees working on different sites located in the region of Paris. Most of the employees commute by private vehicle. Our client is looking at the opportunity of using a new single site for all employees. They want to understand the impact of the new site on the employees’ individual travel time and mode share evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPI Dashboard</title>
      <link>/work/work_89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_89/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners-- CDVIA  -- --  Sector: Data visualisation and process automation.   The context:  CPMS (Collaborative Project Management Services) manages hundreds of projects for rail industry clients in the UK and abroad. The team is growing bigger as the number of projects and the needs to analyse and communicate the staff availability, budget forecast and other company KPI to the management team and the shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HGV flow web mapping</title>
      <link>/work/work_90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_90/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partner: CDVIA  --   Sector: GIS and process automation   The context:  Our client Eiffage is in charge of the construction of the future public transportation stations of the line 16 of the Grand Paris Express in the Paris Area – France. Eiffage need to communicate to their final client, the Société du Grand Paris (SGP), the number of heavy good vehicles (HGV) generated by the project and using the public road network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NRHS Planning Tool</title>
      <link>/work/work_84/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_84/</guid>
      <description>Client:   Partners:   Sector: Process automation   The context: 
Our client (Network Rail High Speed) uses on a daily basis a planning Excel spreadsheet that is transformed every week into a PDF tasks schedule file sent to each member of their staff working on field operations. The data input and transformation processes are all manual, error-prone and time consuming. Many hours are lost every week setting up this planning file.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Open Data Consultants</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>OpenDC has been founded in 2019 by Daniel Marin, engineer from ENSTA ParisTech (France) and INSTN CEA Saclay.  Daniel has over 10 years experience in mathematical modelling for transportation, mobility and pedestrian studies and data analysis, and can work with full proficiency in an English, French or Portuguese speaking environment.  Currently, OpenDC is a company providing contracting work for consultancies and public bodies. OpenDC has also a network of companies specialized in data analysis, pedestrian and transport modelling and ready to partner if a project requires large teams.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>