<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Our projects on OpenDC Ltd - UK</title>
    <link>/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Our projects on OpenDC Ltd - UK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data collection web app</title>
      <link>/work/work_85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_85/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Webapp link: my-places.app   Sector: Web development   The context:  The need for centralised on-site data collection is found in every sector. Tools such as Google Maps or Mapstr can help but they do not provide a dedicate database for your organisation and team. This tool is a free web app, mobile friendly and password protected that enable you to store and comment all your favourite places, without sharing them widely on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile phone data analysis</title>
      <link>/work/work_86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_86/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners: CDVIA  --    Sector: Mobile data analysis   The context:  The Région Sud, a French public administration in charge (not only) of the public transportation service, wants to investigate the use of mobile network data (MND) to understand the transportation needs and behaviours across the South-East region of France. They launched a public tender in May 2019 on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Rail Data lake</title>
      <link>/work/work_87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_87/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners: CDVIA  --    Sector: GIS processing and data analysis   The context:  Our client (Network Rail) manages the rail infrastructure in the UK. Theirs assets (rail, overhead structures etc.) properties are stored in a central database. Modern measurement systems embedded in high speed trains enable to measure some properties of these assets, like the height and stagger of an overhead electrification line at a given location for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimode accessibility</title>
      <link>/work/work_88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_88/</guid>
      <description>Client: Confidential   --  --  Partner: CDVIA  --   Sector: Mobility studies   The context:  Our client (a French public administration) has 800 employees working on different sites located in the region of Paris. Most of the employees commute by private vehicle. Our client is looking at the opportunity of using a new single site for all employees. They want to understand the impact of the new site on the employees’ individual travel time and mode share evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPI Dashboard</title>
      <link>/work/work_89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_89/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners-- CDVIA  -- --  Sector: Data visualisation and process automation.   The context:  CPMS (Collaborative Project Management Services) manages hundreds of projects for rail industry clients in the UK and abroad. The team is growing bigger as the number of projects and the needs to analyse and communicate the staff availability, budget forecast and other company KPI to the management team and the shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HGV flow web mapping</title>
      <link>/work/work_90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_90/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partner: CDVIA  --   Sector: GIS and process automation   The context:  Our client Eiffage is in charge of the construction of the future public transportation stations of the line 16 of the Grand Paris Express in the Paris Area – France. Eiffage need to communicate to their final client, the Société du Grand Paris (SGP), the number of heavy good vehicles (HGV) generated by the project and using the public road network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Pedestrian Modelling Software</title>
      <link>/work/work_91/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_91/</guid>
      <description>Company: Movement Strategies Ltd     Client: Internal project   --  Sector: Pedestrian modelling   What we did:  We developed a pedestrian dynamic assignment software, with an assignment algorithm based on fluid mechanics principles. The tool can assign an unlimited number of pedestrians, at any scale and custom flow density relationship can be implemented. How we use open data or software:  The tool was computed as a QGIS plugin, open source software providing an open source API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Life territories analysis</title>
      <link>/work/work_92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_92/</guid>
      <description>Company: CDVIA     Client: Agence D&amp;A     Sector: Urban planning   What we did:  We created a tool analysing commuting data from the French National Institute of Statistics (INSEE) to help our client understand how commuting data can give insights on how neighbouring cities bound together and define perimeters that can sometimes be at odds with the official administration boundaries. How we use open data or software:  We used French national ordnance survey data from INSEE before it was called open data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mode Choice Estimator</title>
      <link>/work/work_93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_93/</guid>
      <description>Company: CDVIA     Client: Internal project   --  Sector: Transport modelling   What we did:  We helped our client build a public transport assignment tool plugged into their in-house private transport assignment tool. We then collected open data of observed mode choice for commute at an aggregate level. Using private and public transportation travel times derived from the assignment tools, we have inferred a simple model giving a mode probability as a function of the difference of travel time between public and private transportation options.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobile Network Data project</title>
      <link>/work/work_94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/work/work_94/</guid>
      <description>Company: Telefónica UK   -- Confidential  --  Client: Confidential Transport for London (TfL)   --  --  Sector: Data analytics in transport   What we did:  Our project aimed to build Origin-Destination (OD) matrices split by modes in a dense and populated region using mobile network data fused with external datasets. As part of a major telco company, in a joint project involving two transport consultancies, we managed the team of analysts in charge of collecting, cleaning, filtering, scaling and analysing the mobile network data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>