<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Our Work on OpenDC Ltd - UK</title>
    <link>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Our Work on OpenDC Ltd - UK</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-uk</language>
    
	<atom:link href="c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SENSE Pedestrian Assignment Software</title>
      <link>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_01/</guid>
      <description>Client: Movement Strategies Ltd     Sector: Pedestrian modelling   
 What we did:  We developed a pedestrian dynamic assignment software, with an assignment algorithm based on fluid mechanics principles. The tool can assign an unlimited number of pedestrians, at any scale and cutom flow desnity relationship can be implemented. How we use open data or software:  The tool was computed as a QGIS plugin, open source software providing an open source API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bassins de vie du Grand Paris</title>
      <link>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_02/</guid>
      <description>Client: Agence D&amp;A     Sector: Urban planning   
 What we did:  We created a toll analysing commuting open data from the French ordnance survey (INSEE) to help our client understand how commuting data can give insights on how nieghbouring cities bound together and define perimeters that are sometimes at odds with the official administration boundaries. How we use open data or software:  We used French national ordnance survey data from INSEE before it was called open data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mode Choice Estimator</title>
      <link>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_03/</guid>
      <description>Client: CDVIA     Sector: Transport modelling   
 What we did:  We helped our client build a public transport assignment tool plugged into their in-house private transport assignment tool. We then collected open data of observed mode choice for commute at an aggregate level. Using privtae and public transportation travel times derived from the assignment tool, we have infered a simple model giving a mode probablity as a function of the travel time difference.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project EDMOND</title>
      <link>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>c:///Users/dmarin/Dropbox/Pro/info/Git/Project_repositories/opendc_website/open-dc/public/work/work_04/</guid>
      <description>Client: Transport for London (TfL)      Sector: Data analytics in transport    
 What we did:  The TfL EDMOND project aimed to build Origin-Destination (OD) matrices in the Greater London Authority (GLA) unsing mobile network data fused with external datasets.  As part of the Telefónica UK team in a joint project involving two major consultancies (Jacobs and AECOM), we managed the team of analysts at Telefónica in charge of collecting, cleaning, filtering, scaling and analysing the mobile network data.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>