<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Os nossos projetos on OpenDC Ltd - Pt</title>
    <link>/pt/work/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Os nossos projetos on OpenDC Ltd - Pt</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>pt</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/pt/work/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Data collection web app</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_85/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_85/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Webapp link: my-places.app   Sector: Web development   The context:  The need for centralised on-site data collection is found in every sector. Tools such as Google Maps or Mapstr can help but they do not provide a dedicate database for your organisation and team. This tool is a free web app, mobile friendly and password protected that enable you to store and comment all your favourite places, without sharing them widely on the web.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mobility analysis with mobile phone data</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_86/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_86/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners: CDVIA  --    Sector: Mobile data analysis   The context:  The Région Sud, a French public administration in charge (not only) of the public transportation service, wants to investigate the use of mobile network data (MND) to understand the transportation needs and behaviours across the South-East region of France. They launched a public tender in May 2019 on this topic.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Network Rail Data lake</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_87/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_87/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners: CDVIA  --    Sector: GIS processing and data analysis   The context:  Our client (Network Rail) manages the rail infrastructure in the UK. Theirs assets (rail, overhead structures etc.) properties are stored in a central database. Modern measurement systems embedded in high speed trains enable to measure some properties of these assets, like the height and stagger of an overhead electrification line at a given location for example.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Multimode workplace accessibility</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_88/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_88/</guid>
      <description>Client: Confidential    --  --  Partner: CDVIA  --   Sector: Mobility studies   The context:  Our client (a French public administration) has 800 employees working on different sites located in the region of Paris. Most of the employees commute by private vehicle. Our client is looking at the opportunity of using a new single site for all employees. They want to understand the impact of the new site on the employees’ individual travel time and mode share evolution.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>KPI Dashboard</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_89/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_89/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partners-- CDVIA  -- --  Sector: Data visualisation and process automation.   The context:  CPMS (Collaborative Project Management Services) manages hundreds of projects for rail industry clients in the UK and abroad. The team is growing bigger as the number of projects and the needs to analyse and communicate the staff availability, budget forecast and other company KPI to the management team and the shareholders.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HGV flow web mapping</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_90/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_90/</guid>
      <description>Client: Eiffage  --   --  Partner: CDVIA  --   Sector: GIS and process automation   The context:  Our client Eiffage is in charge of the construction of the future public transportation stations of the line 16 of the Grand Paris Express in the Paris Area – France. Eiffage need to communicate to their final client, the Société du Grand Paris (SGP), the number of heavy good vehicles (HGV) generated by the project and using the public road network.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Software de atribuição pedestre SENSE</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_91/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_91/</guid>
      <description>Companhia: Movement Strategies Ltd     Cliente: Projecto Interno   --  Sector: Modelação pedestre   O que fizemos:  Desenvolvemos um software de atribuição dinâmica pedestre, com um algoritmo de atribuição baseado em princípios de Mecânica de Fluidos. A ferramenta pode atribuir um número ilimitado de pedestres, a qualquer escala e é possível implementar uma relação fluxo-densidade personalizada. Como usamos open data e o software:  A ferramenta foi desenvolvida como um QGIS plugin, software open source que providencia uma API open source.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Territórios de vida dentro da Grande Paris</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_92/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_92/</guid>
      <description>Companhia: CDVIA     Cliente: Agence D&amp;A     Sector: Planeamento Urbano   O que fizemos:  Desenvolvemos uma ferramenta analisando dados pendulares do Instituto Nacional de Estatística Francês (INSEE) para ajudar o cliente a entender como é que dados pendulares podem fornecer ideias à cerca da forma como cidades vizinhas estão conectadas e definem perímetros que muitas vezes estão em contradição com as fronteiras oficiais de administração.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Estimador de escolha de modos de transporte</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_93/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_93/</guid>
      <description>Companhia: CDVIA     Cliente: Projecto interno   --  Sector: Modelação de transporte   O que fizemos:  Ajudámos o nosso cliente a desenvolver uma ferramenta pública de atribuição de transportes com conexão à sua pŕopria ferramenta de atribuição privada e in-house. Prosseguimos à recolha de open data do modelo de escolha observado para comutar a um nível agregado. Usando tempos de viagem de transportes públicos e privados deduzidos das ferramentas de atribuição, inferimos um modelo simples que dá a probabilidade de um modo em função da diferença no tempo de viagem entre opções de transporte público e privado.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Projecto de Dados de Rede Móvel</title>
      <link>/pt/work/work_94/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/pt/work/work_94/</guid>
      <description>Companhia: Telefónica UK   -- Confidencial  --  Cliente: Confidencial Transport for London (TfL)   --  --  Sector: Análise de dados em transporte   O que fizemos:  O nosso projecto visou desenvolver matrizes Origem-Destino (OD) divididas por modos numa região densa e populosa usando dados de redes telefónicas em conjunção com conjuntos de dados externos. Como parte de uma grande empresa de telecomunicações, num projecto conjunto envolvendo duas consultadorias de transporte, gerimos a equipa de analistas responsável pela recolha, limpeza, filtração, escalamento e análise dos dados da rede móvel.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>