<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Services OpenDC on OpenDC Ltd - Fr</title>
    <link>/fr/services/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Services OpenDC on OpenDC Ltd - Fr</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>fr-fr</language>
    
	<atom:link href="/fr/services/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fr - Analysis of Open Datasets</title>
      <link>/fr/services/service_01/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/services/service_01/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC can help you find among the thousands of webpages the open data sets that can help your organisation unlock new insights. Some of this data will be too big to be anlaysed by usual tools like Excel. OpenDC can help you load and analyse this data using open source programming tools such as Python libraries or PostgreSQL databases. Once this data is identified and loaded, OpenDC can help you analyse the patterns in the data, cross the information with external independant datasets to find correlations, answer the questions you have asked and the ones you have not.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fr -Mapping and Visualisation</title>
      <link>/fr/services/service_02/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/services/service_02/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC mainly uses the QGIS framework as a Geographic Information System (GIS) tool. With QGIS, OpenDC can provide communicative maps as well as perform advanced GIS analysis such as the analysis of catchment areas but also advanced routing features. OpenDC can also provide GIS training in general and on QGIS in particular. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can help you use GIS features if you are working for a</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fr - QGIS Plugin Development</title>
      <link>/fr/services/service_03/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/services/service_03/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC can develop for you custom QGIS plguins under the QGIS API. Note that any QGIS plugin that is publicaly released needs to be open-source. 
How this service can help your organisation You might be interested in a custom QGIS plugin if you are working for a
 Non Governmental Organisation (NGO) with interesting geographical datasets that you want to make available to the GIS community in order to enable the wide analysis of this data set.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fr - Assistance on process automation</title>
      <link>/fr/services/service_04/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/services/service_04/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do Fr - OpenDC mainly uses open source languages but stay pragmatic when a language or an application is popular but not open source. Therefore OpenDC uses VBA to automate your processes on any Microsoft Office application, and Python for other applications. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can help you use automate your processes if You have standard manipulations under Excel that regularly take a lot of your time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fr - Assistance on mobility studies</title>
      <link>/fr/services/service_05/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/services/service_05/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC&amp;rsquo;s founder has over 10 years experience in transport and pedestrian modelling, working in Paris, London and Guinea Conakry. OpenDC can help strengthen your team with advanced modelling and project management skills. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can help you in your mobility project if you are working for a
 Local council and want to be advised on a mobility study you would like to launch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fr - Advice on the use of mobile phone and GPS data</title>
      <link>/fr/services/service_06/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/fr/services/service_06/</guid>
      <description>What OpenDC can do OpenDC&amp;rsquo;s founder has developed an expertise on the use of mobile phone data (GSM) and GPS data to understand people movement. This expertise involves the collection of the data, the storage, the cleansing process, various filtering processes using different mathematical tools, the acaling, bias correction, aggregation, analysis and visualisation. 
How this service can help your organisation OpenDC can assist you with GPS and mobile network data if you are working for a</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>